<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khalid Hussain</title>
    <link>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Khalid Hussain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khalid-hussain&#34;&gt;Khalid Hussain&lt;/a&gt; 1438</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 22:49:21 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://khalid-hussain.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Pandoc</title>
      <link>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/introduction-to-pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 22:49:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/introduction-to-pandoc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This article is dedicated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/moaaz.mahdi&#34;&gt;Moaaz Mahdi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will introduce you to a brilliant program called
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pandoc.org&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnmacfarlane.net/&#34;&gt;John
MacFarlane&lt;/a&gt;. Pandoc is a document converter which
allows for conversion between different document formats. The list of
supported document formats is overwhelming but ones which might be of
universal interest are: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Office_Open_XML&#34;&gt;Microsoft
Docx&lt;/a&gt;, HTML, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www
.latex-project.org/about/&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, and Epub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandoc may not seem that useful in the beginning but as we go through this
article, you will come to love the different scenarios it can be applied to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandoc gets its name from a combination of the words ‘pan-’ and ‘document’.
‘Pan-’, in its combining form, means, “involving all of a (specified) group or
region, e.g., Pan-American”&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:pan&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:pan&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, thus Pan-Document, and finally Pandoc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, download the installer for your system. Pandoc is available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/releases/download/1.18/pandoc-1.18-windows.msi&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/releases/download/1.18/pandoc-1.18-1-amd64.deb&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/releases/download/1.18/pandoc-1.18-osx.pkg&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;. The latest version as of this writing is v1.18. Pandoc releases can be viewed on its GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/pandoc/releases&#34;&gt;Releases page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation methods may vary slightly depending on the system but it should be straightforward nonetheless. Do note that Pandoc is a command-line application and thus you will not find any shortcuts in the regular places (for Windows, this would be the Start menu and Desktop). You can check if your installation was successful by opening your command prompt and entering,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pandoc --version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which would produce the following (if using v1.18; v1.17 and earlier will show different information)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pandoc 1.18
Compiled with pandoc-types 1.17.0.4, texmath 0.8.6.6, highlighting-kate 0.6.3
Default user data directory: C:\Users\Khalid\AppData\Roaming\pandoc
Copyright (C) 2006-2016 John MacFarlane
Web:  http://pandoc.org
This is free software; see the source for copying conditions.
There is no warranty, not even for merchantability or fitness
for a particular purpose.

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:pan&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pan.&amp;rdquo; Merriam-Webster.com. Accessed November 6, 2016. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/pan&#34;&gt;http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/pan&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:pan&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salawāt on the Prophet (ﷺ) in documents</title>
      <link>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/salawat-on-the-prophet-in-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 16:19:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/salawat-on-the-prophet-in-documents/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whoever sends blessings upon me, Allāh will send blessings upon him tenfold.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Muslim (384).&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will help introduce you to the different methods of sending salutations upon the greatest man to have ever lived, Prophet Muḥammad (Peace be upon him), along with some of the complications that occur due to intricacies of computers. The article will not discuss the issue from a fiqh perspective as there are already many good articles regarding it, for example, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://abdurrahman.org/2014/12/24/the-obligation-of-invoking-peace-and-blessings-on-the-prophet-in-a-complete-form-and-avoid-using-abbreviations-like-pbuh-saw-etc/&#34;&gt;AbdurRahman.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending salutations upon the Prophet (Peace be upon him) is an important act of worship which is, unfortunately, done half-heartedly when it comes to writing in this age. The article takes the following into consideration,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salutations upon the Prophet (Peace be upon him) must be done in full at all times, whether in Arabic or English. &amp;lsquo;(Pbuh)&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;(ṣ)&amp;rdquo; or &amp;lsquo;(saw)&amp;rdquo; and all its variants are unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convenience. Salutations upon the Prophet should be made convenient for the user. Despite the advent of computers and word processors, you will still find people who find it difficult to send salutions upon the Prophet (Peace be upon him) in full.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consistency. Methods introduced for sending salutations should help avoid typos and enable its semantics to be dealth with separately (you&amp;rsquo;ll understand this better in one of the following sections).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;english-or-arabic&#34;&gt;English or Arabic?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have only ever used word processor software to put thoughts to paper/file/screen will think that this is probably a personal preference. Others, however, are aware of the limitations of certain files/methods and may be at times forced to type in English (or any other Latin based character set) even if their preference is Arabic. This and related issues will be discussed in this section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fonts consists of many characters from different alphabets of different languages. To get an idea of what this means, if on a Windows machine, open the application called &amp;lsquo;Character Map&amp;rsquo;. Browse through some of the common fonts and you&amp;rsquo;ll realize the amount of effort required to create a single font.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/salawat-on-prophet/character-map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Character Map&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Character Map
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Fonts consist of letters, special characters, joined characters, space, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Typographic_ligature&#34;&gt;ligatures&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fleuron_(typography)&#34;&gt;fleurons&lt;/a&gt; at times. Each character in a font is represented by an address with which programs can realize the difference between say, Greek &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; and the English &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt;. Fonts which include support for different languages are usually represented using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UTF-8&#34;&gt;UTF-8&lt;/a&gt; system, a sort of subset of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unicode&#34;&gt;Unicode&lt;/a&gt;. Addresses in this system are represented as &lt;code&gt;U+XXXX&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;XXXX&lt;/code&gt; is a set of hexadecimal digits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arabic language has always been attached to Islam and many conventions have now become a trademark of the language which even disbelievers learn, such as the Salām (greeting). You will be pleased to know that some have even moved into fonts as individual characters. Some of these are presented as follows, courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arabic_script_in_Unicode&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/salawat-on-prophet/arabic-symbols-web.png&#34; alt=&#34;Some Arabic symbols and their Unicode addresses&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Some Arabic symbols and their Unicode addresses
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The character of concern here is the &amp;ldquo;Peace be upon him&amp;rdquo; symbol that occurs at the address &lt;code&gt;U+FDFA&lt;/code&gt;. To see this in action, if on a Windows machine with at least Microsoft Office 2013, open a new blank document. Then type in the address of the required symbol, &lt;code&gt;U+FDFA&lt;/code&gt; in this case. When you&amp;rsquo;re done, before you move the cursor anywhere else or type space, press &lt;code&gt;ALT + X&lt;/code&gt; and your code should automatically switch to the respective symbol. This is demonstrated as follows,&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/salawat-on-prophet/word-salawat-logo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Typing Salawāt symbol in Microsoft Word 2013&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Typing Salawāt symbol in Microsoft Word 2013
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Please note that all fonts do not have support for this symbol. However, most of the popular fonts do, so it should not pose a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;automation&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we know how to enter the salutations symbol in at least Microsoft Word 2013, let&amp;rsquo;s see how we can automate the process since the procedure is cumbersome if you have many instances to type. This section will cover instructions for a Microsoft Windows environment as this is the system I have. The following are some of the ways some sort of automation may be achieved,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save all required symbols in a separate text file from which you can copy the required ones when needed. To help with managing all your copies and pastes, you can use a clipboard manager, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://ditto-cp.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Ditto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an automation script with software like &lt;a href=&#34;http://ahkscript.org/&#34;&gt;AutoHotkey&lt;/a&gt;. To help you get started, you can check out my bootstrapped project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khalid-hussain/IslamicTextAHK&#34;&gt;IslamicTextAHK&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khalid-hussain/IslamicTextAHK/blob/master/islamicTextAHK.ahk&#34;&gt;islamicTextAHK.ahk&lt;/a&gt; file. This option is better than the first as it&amp;rsquo;s faster and universal (i.e., it works in all applications across the system). The shorcut key combination can also be edited to one&amp;rsquo;s preference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following shows input on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s website which uses an AutoHotkey script I&amp;rsquo;ve created for myself.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/salawat-on-prophet/facebook_input.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Facebook input&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Facebook input
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has become easier than ever to send salutations on the Prophet (Peace be upon him). All it takes is some time to understand how fonts work and to get acquainted with the techniques that enable one to efficiently input (or expand) text. I hope this short introduction is enough to encourage you to send proper salutations upon the Prophet (Peace be upon him) as opposed to the &amp;lsquo;saw&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;pbuh&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;ṣ&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; that have become prevalent in online text.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to know Microsoft Word Styles</title>
      <link>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/microsoft-word-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 08:43:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/microsoft-word-styles/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After proofreading a number of theses and articles, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that most
students in IIUM don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use (Microsoft Word) styles to add structure
to their documents. This short article will get you familiar with using Microsoft Word styles. We will be using Microsoft Word 2013 on Windows, however, this should also apply to Microsoft Word 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document styles are a way to add semantic structure to your documents. This
provides several benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Helps in automatically creating a &amp;lsquo;Table of Contents&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;List of Figures&amp;rsquo;, and
&amp;lsquo;List of Tables&amp;rsquo;. You will also make no mistakes in numbering headings and
subheadings, given that all of them are defined properly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Helps in editing several items of the same &amp;lsquo;style&amp;rsquo; at once, which in turn
saves time and ensures that the formatting is applied throughout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enables one to easily export a Microsoft Word document to other formats, such
as &lt;code&gt;EPUB&lt;/code&gt; for ebook readers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Makes one more conscious of the document structure which in turn improves
one&amp;rsquo;s writing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The options for &amp;lsquo;styles&amp;rsquo; can be seen from the &amp;lsquo;HOME&amp;rsquo; tab in the document window.
The default selection window is quite limited in that only a few styles are
shown at a time and not all styles are shown.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/ribbon-styles-highlight.png&#34; alt=&#34;Styles section in Home tab of Microsoft Word&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Styles section in Home tab of Microsoft Word
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;styles-pane&#34;&gt;Styles Pane&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you can open the dedicated Styles pane by pressing the small arrow on
the bottom right of the Styles section. The Styles pane lists all the styles
available for the current document.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/styles-arrow.png&#34; alt=&#34;Styles Pane arrow&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Styles Pane arrow
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After clicking the arrow, you will be presented with a separate Styles pane that
will list all styles used in the current document.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/styles-pane.png&#34; alt=&#34;Styles Pane&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Styles Pane
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;New styles can be created and current styles can be edited by right-clicking a
listed style and clicking &amp;ldquo;Modify&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/modify-style-dialog.png&#34; alt=&#34;Modify Style dialog&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Modify Style dialog
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;simple-example&#34;&gt;Simple Example&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s try a simple example. Open a new document and write out a few paragraphs
along with a few headings.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/simple-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Simple document&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Simple document
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now apply &amp;ldquo;Heading 1&amp;rdquo; styles to all your headings by highlighting your headings
one by one and then selecting the style &amp;ldquo;Heading 1&amp;rdquo; from the Styles pane. You
should have something as follows.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/simple-example-headings.png&#34; alt=&#34;Simple document with &amp;#34;heading 1&amp;#34; styles&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Simple document with &amp;#34;heading 1&amp;#34; styles
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-now&#34;&gt;What Now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things you can try out immediately with your simple example
document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;generating-table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Generating Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To generate a &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo; for the document, head to the beginning of the
document, click on the &amp;ldquo;References&amp;rdquo; tab and select the &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo;
option. It is highlighted in the screenshot below.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/table-of-contents.png&#34; alt=&#34;Table of Contents option&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Table of Contents option
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Select a &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo; style and you should have something as follows.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/table-of-contents-preview.png&#34; alt=&#34;Table of Contents Preview&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Table of Contents Preview
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Great things to note, page numbers can be automatically updated as you continue
writing your document, you &lt;strong&gt;do not&lt;/strong&gt; have to manually input page numbers in
your &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo;. Similarly, all your headings, sub-headings, and sub-
sub-headings, are automatically detected and updated in the &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo;
as you write your document. Update of the &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo; is not live
though, so every time you want to update your &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo;, head over to
your &amp;ldquo;Table of Contents&amp;rdquo; and click on the &amp;ldquo;Update Table&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; option. This can be
seen in the following screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/table-of-contents-update.png&#34; alt=&#34;Updating Table of Contents&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Updating Table of Contents
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the option presents a dialog with two options, namely, &amp;ldquo;Update page
numbers only&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Update entire table&amp;rdquo;. The former is good if no need headings
were added to your document since the last time the Table of Contents was
updated. The latter on the other hand should be used if new headings have been
added to your document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;change-document-theme&#34;&gt;Change document theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since your document is properly structured, changing themes is mostly a single-
click affair. To try out a few different themes/designs, head over to the
&amp;ldquo;Design&amp;rdquo; tab and try some of the different themes available. The simple example
document is shown below with a different theme than the default.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/ms-word-styles/simple-example-theme.png&#34; alt=&#34;Simple Example with different theme&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Simple Example with different theme
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this short article is enough for introducing the concept of document
styles in Microsoft Word and that you can make good use of them in your future
documents. I&amp;rsquo;m still working on the comment system, so if you have any
suggestions or comments, please send them directly to my GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/good-to-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 12:33:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalid-hussain.github.io/post/good-to-great/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog. This is my first attempt at a blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll document interesting things I come across. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Atque rerum sequi libero eveniet tempore nostrum deleniti, cum iusto ullam maiores id odio aut earum incidunt vel! Atque totam, odio possimus? Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Perferendis sunt, et eos perspiciatis at officia omnis, libero, ipsum sed similique esse praesentium amet quae aliquid id aspernatur saepe facere labore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Aliquid voluptas ut earum enim itaque harum commodi corporis nam quasi, dolor iusto placeat minus provident eum! Nostrum placeat soluta omnis possimus. Testing SVG images,&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;./images/output.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Steve Francia&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Steve Francia
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cpp&#34;&gt;int main(){
  cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; endl;
  return 0;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pannable-image&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>